- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[silly upbeat music]
[愚蠢欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
[phone ringing]
[电话铃声]
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
Will someone please
answer this phone?
有人请吗
接这个电话吗？
I'm busy.
我很忙。
- I'll get it, Squidward.
- 我会得到它，章鱼哥。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- [groaning]
Oh, almost.
哦，差不多了。
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
哦，哦，哦，哦。
Ah, not that time.
啊，不是那个时候。
Whoa! Whoa!
哇！哇！
- [groans]
- [shouts]
- [呻吟]
- [喊叫]
- Krusty Krab.
- 蟹堡王。
I'm sorry, we don't deliver
to that neighborhood.
抱歉，我们不送货
到那个街区。
- [shouts]
- [喊叫]
Who don't deliver
to what neighborhood?
谁不送货
到哪个街区？
- [unintelligible grumbling]
- [难以理解的抱怨]
We don't deliver to RandomLand!
我们不送货到 RandomLand！
- And why not?
- 为什么不呢？
- Because I heard
the place is crazy
- 因为我听说
这个地方太疯狂了
and no delivery fish
has ever returned.
并且没有送货鱼
曾经回来过。
- Squidward, just because it's
a preposterous neighborhood
- 章鱼哥，只是因为它是
荒唐的街区
where the laws of nature
change randomly
自然法则在那里
随机改变
and the people are all
cuckoo...
人们都是
杜鹃...
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
- Don't mean the Krusty Krab
- 不是指蟹堡王
won't attempt
to take their money.
不会尝试
拿他们的钱。
- [unintelligible grumbling]
- [难以理解的抱怨]
- Mm-hmm.
20 minutes.
- 嗯嗯。
20分钟。
- Well, I'm not cuckoo
enough to go to RandomLand.
- 好吧，我不是杜鹃
足够去RandomLand了。
- [giggling]
- [咯咯笑]
- Someone is cuckoo
enough to go.
- 有人是杜鹃
足够了。
- So what are you two
yentas gabbing about?
- 所以你们两个是什么
元塔斯闲聊？
- Flick.
- [groans]
- 轻弹。
- [呻吟]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
The delivery will be made,
将进行交货，
and the mission will be
accomplished, sir!
使命将是
完成了，先生！
Um...how do I
get to RandomLand?
嗯...我该怎么办
去随机大陆吗？
- Well,
that's the thing, boy-o.
- 嗯，
就是这样，男孩。
No one really knows.
没有人真正知道。
You just walk around...
你随便走走...
randomly.
随机的。
- Well, that's how
I usually get around.
- 嗯，就是这样
我通常都会四处走动。
[upbeat organ music]
[欢快的管风琴音乐]
♪ ♪
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
Ar, ar, ar,
ar, ar, ar!
阿尔，阿尔，阿尔，
啊，啊，啊！
Zoink!
How's that?
佐因克！
怎么样？
[yells]
[喊叫]
- [laughs]
That idiot's getting
- [笑]
那个白痴越来越
lost for sure.
肯定输了。
- You're probably right.
You better go with him.
- 你可能是对的。
你最好和他一起去。
- Well, of course,
that makes sense...
- 嗯，当然，
这是有道理的...
What?
[unintelligible shouting]
什么？
[难以理解的喊叫]
[yelling]
[大喊]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- [giggling]
- [咯咯笑]
♪ Random walking ♪
♪ 随意行走 ♪
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
Hey, Squidward
I don't think this...
嘿，章鱼哥
我不认为这...
♪ Walking random
thing is working ♪
♪ 随意行走
事情正在运作 ♪
- SpongeBob?
- 海绵宝宝？
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
Oh, no!
SpongeBob has disappeared.
哦，不！
海绵宝宝失踪了。
What ever will I do?
我会做什么？
[laughs]
[笑]
♪ SpongeBob gone
hallelujah ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝走了
哈利路亚♪
♪ SpongeBob gone,
I don't give a tuna ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝走了，
我不给金枪鱼♪
Hummuna-what?
胡姆纳-什么？
[shouting]
[喊叫]
[yelling]
[大喊]
- Beep, beep!
- Of course.
- 嘟嘟嘟！
- 当然。
- Beep, beep!
- [grunts]
- 嘟嘟嘟！
- [咕哝]
- Beep, beep, beep!
- Go around.
- 嘟嘟嘟，嘟嘟嘟！
- 四处走走。
The fun never ends with us,
huh, Squidward?
我们的乐趣永无止境，
哈，章鱼哥？
- [yelling]
- [大喊]
- [laughing]
- [笑]
[goofy frantic music]
[愚蠢疯狂的音乐]
♪ ♪
- Good Neptune!
You're hideous.
- 好海王星！
你真丑陋。
- You too.
- 你也是。
But somehow you still
retain your allure.
但不知怎的你还是
保留你的魅力。
[giggles]
- Hm.
[咯咯笑]
- 嗯。
Well, here we are
in RandomLand.
好吧，我们到了
在随机之地。
Sure is for that.
当然是为了这个。
Sure is for that?
[sighs]
确定是为了这个吗？
[叹气]
The neighborhood must
be affecting my speech.
邻里必须
影响我的演讲。
Come on, let's put our
grind to the nose stone.
来吧，让我们把我们的
磨到鼻石。
- Aw, Squidward,
can't we take a minute
- 噢，章鱼哥，
我们不能花一分钟吗
to smell and stop the roses?
闻并阻止玫瑰花？
[laughing]
Smell and stop the roses!
[笑]
闻一闻并停止玫瑰花！
I meant stop and smell the--
[laughing]
我的意思是停下来闻闻——
[笑]
[gasps]
[喘气]
- [unintelligible gibberish]
- [难以理解的胡言乱语]
[creatures beeping
and squeaking]
[生物发出嘟嘟声
和吱吱声]
- Ah. Hm? Ah.
- 啊。嗯？啊。
- [grumbling]
- [抱怨]
Now where are we?
现在我们在哪里？
- There's an exit.
- 有一个出口。
Come on!
快点！
- Huh?
- 啊？
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
Huh?
[grunts]
啊？
[咕哝]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
- What is it?
- 这是什么？
[doorbells ringing and echoing]
[门铃响起并回响]
Oh, it's those
lost delivery boys!
哦，就是那些
送货小哥丢了！
Let's go and--
我们走吧——
- I'll take that bag.
- 我会拿那个包。
- One delivery's
as good as another.
- 一次送货
和另一个一样好。
- This delivery is property
of the Krusty Krab
- 此交付是财产
蟹堡王的
until it is in the hands
of the person who ordered it!
直到到手为止
订购它的人！
But, ma'am, you can place
an order any time.
但是，女士，你可以把
随时下订单。
- [yelps]
- [尖叫声]
[chomping]
[咀嚼]
- We're sorry, your call
cannot be completed as dialed.
- 很抱歉，您的来电
无法按拨号完成。
- Oh, whoo!
- 哦，哇！
- [groans]
Hand me the address.
- [呻吟]
把地址递给我。
86 Screwball Street.
86 怪诞街。
There's a hole in it.
里面有一个洞。
- Ooh.
- 哦。
I'm a collector.
我是一个收藏家。
- [sighs]
No taste for accounting.
- [叹气]
对会计没有兴趣。
Why don't we just
arbitrarily knock on doors?
我们为什么不直接
随意敲门？
- Hey, now you're
thinking random!
- 嘿，现在你是
思维随意！
Yeah!
There!
是的！
那里！
Screwball Street.
螺旋街。
Knock, knock.
敲，敲。
- Ooh.
[laughs]
- 哦。
[笑]
- Excuse me, ma'am,
did you order a Krabby Patty?
- 对不起，女士，
你点了蟹肉饼吗？
- Can I dunk it in cocoa
like my marshmallows?
- 我可以把它泡在可可里吗
就像我的棉花糖一样？
both: Huh?
两人：啊？
- [giggling]
- [咯咯笑]
- Ooh, may I?
- 哦，可以吗？
[gulping]
[吞咽]
[laughing]
Tough mallows.
[笑]
坚韧的锦葵。
Could be more marshy.
可能会更加沼泽。
[laughing]
[笑]
- Here, brush your tooth.
- 来，刷牙。
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
- [squeaking]
- [吱吱声]
- This whole place
is inside out,
- 这整个地方
是由内而外的，
so why not
an upside-down house?
那么为什么不呢
颠倒的房子？
[doorbell rings]
[门铃响]
- Whoo-hoo!
- 呼呼！
- Oh, hmm.
- 哦，嗯。
For sale.
出售。
- Hello, handsome.
- 你好，帅哥。
- Oh.
[laughs]
- 哦。
[笑]
Well, wouldn't I like you
to get me to like you knowing
嗯，我不会喜欢你吗
让我知道你喜欢我
you would get me
better to know...you?
你会得到我
更好地了解...你？
- Hello, anyone home?
- 你好，有人在家吗？
Maybe I should say
that upside down.
也许我应该说
那个颠倒了。
Ooh, I know!
哦，我知道了！
Hello, anyone home?
你好，有人在家吗？
[gasps]
Ooh, upside-down cake!
[喘气]
哦，颠倒的蛋糕！
Oops.
哎呀。
- I see you've got an eye
for home design, son.
-我看你有眼光
对于家居设计，儿子。
You are gonna love this house.
There's no downside.
你一定会喜欢这所房子的。
没有什么缺点。
You get it,
no downside? Ha, ha!
你明白了，
没有缺点吗？哈，哈！
- Oh, I'm not looking to buy.
I'm just delivering
- 哦，我不想买。
我只是在送货
for the Krabby Krust.
为蟹壳。
- This bag is mine.
- 这个包是我的。
[laughs]
- Oh!
[笑]
- 哦！
[shouting]
[喊叫]
Squidward,
the bag has been snatched!
章鱼哥，
包被抢了！
- Well, that's that.
Let's go home.
- 嗯，就是这样。
我们回家吧。
- No way, Squidward.
That Patty Krabby
- 没门，章鱼哥。
那个帕蒂·克拉比
belongs to the order
who person'd it!
属于订单
谁干的！
Huh?
Come back here!
啊？
回到这里吧！
- I hate my life.
- 我讨厌我的生活。
- [squeaks]
- [吱吱声]
[yelps]
[尖叫声]
- [giggling]
- [咯咯笑]
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
- [giggling]
- [咯咯笑]
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
[shaver buzzing]
[剃须刀嗡嗡声]
Whoo!
呼！
[laughs]
[笑]
[shaver buzzing]
[剃须刀嗡嗡声]
- Ugh?
- 呃？
- [giggling]
- [咯咯笑]
[panting]
Are you two done?
[气喘吁吁]
你们两个忙完了吗？
both: Not yet!
两人：还没有！
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
Ah, these drumsticks are harder
啊，这些鸡腿更硬
to walk on than high heels.
比高跟鞋还要走路。
- Well, it's all
about balance.
- 好吧，就这样了
关于平衡。
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- [clears throat]
- [清喉咙]
- I order you to return that
delivery to the Krusty Krab!
- 我命令你归还那个
送货到蟹堡王啦！
- Where's your manners?
Haven't you heard of knocking?
- 你的礼貌呢？
你没听说过敲门吗？
- Go ahead, knock.
- 来吧，敲门。
- Just what I wanted,
- 正是我想要的，
a new bag.
[giggling]
一个新包。
[咯咯笑]
- Let's go home.
- 我们回家吧。
- But...what about the patty?
- 但是...肉饼呢？
- Ah!
- 啊！
- [chatters]
- [闲聊]
[door slams]
[关门声]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
[intense music]
[激烈的音乐]
- Oh, this place
is a nightmare!
- 哦，这个地方
是一场噩梦！
No one's ever returned.
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
We're doomed to live
in this insane asylum.
我们注定要活下去
在这个疯人院里。
- Oh, boy!
That means we can stay
- 哦，孩子！
这意味着我们可以留下来
and deliver the patty.
并交付肉饼。
- We made the delivery.
- 我们已经发货了。
Mission accomplished.
任务完成了。
- But--but Mr. Krabs...
- 但是 - 但是蟹老板先生...
- If the foot were on the other
shoe, Krabs would do the same.
- 如果脚在另一只脚上
鞋子，蟹老板也会做同样的事情。
- No, Squidward, Mr. Krabs!
He's right there.
- 不，章鱼哥，蟹老板！
他就在那里。
- [gasps]
He's probably looking for us.
- [喘气]
他可能正在找我们。
Mr. Krabs!
蟹老板！
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
- But we haven't
made our delivery!
- 但我们还没有
交货了！
Mr. Krabs!
Yeow!
蟹老板！
哟！
Ah, ow!
啊，噢！
[upbeat frantic music]
[欢快疯狂的音乐]
♪ ♪
both: Huh?
两人：啊？
It's the Krusty Krab!
这是蟹堡王！
[both panting]
[两人都气喘吁吁]
Hey, Mr. Krabs,
thanks for showing us
嘿，蟹老板，
感谢您向我们展示
the way out of RandomLand.
离开随机之地的出路。
- Excuse me, I'm not Krabs.
- 对不起，我不是蟹蟹。
The name is Rodger,
我的名字叫罗杰，
and I walked all the way
from 86 Screwball Street
我一路走来
从 86 螺丝球街
to complainabout never
getting my delivery.
抱怨从不
收到我的送货。
- Oh, your delivery,
my good man.
- 哦，你的送货，
我的好人。
- [gulping]
- [吞咽]
- Mission accomplished.
Better late than never.
- 任务完成。
迟到总比不到好。
- [crying]
- [哭泣]
Better never!
If it's late,
最好永远不要！
如果来晚了的话
it's free.
它是免费的。
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
What?
什么？